<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Chenla: weblog</title>
 <link href="http://chenla.la/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://chenla.la/"/>
 <updated>2014-06-13T11:54:47+07:00</updated>
 <id>http://chenla.la</id>
 <author>
   <name>Brad Collins</name>
   <email>brad@chenal.la</email>
 </author>
 
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Failure of Imagination</title>
   <link href="http://chenla.la/2014/04/10/A-Failure-Of-Imagination.html"/>
   <updated>2014-04-10T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.paperplanes.de/2014/04/10/A-Failure-Of-Imagination</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
McGuire took Benjamin to one side and stared at him intently before
saying &quot;I just want to say one word to you. Just one word.&quot;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&quot;Yes, sir,&quot; Benjamin said.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&quot;Are you listening?&quot; McGuire said.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&quot;Yes, I am.&quot;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&quot;Plastics.&quot;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&quot;Exactly how do you mean?&quot;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&amp;#x2013; The Graduate, 1967
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
The human mind is a pattern recognition machine.  The brain
relentlessly takes in sensory input, and matches that input against
memories and then makes a mental model that fits the sensory input
into that mental model.  The result, which is the illusion our brain
creates, is a best guess at what the world is.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So long as the brain can relate new input with existing memories,
analogies and metaphors, it does a pretty good job of understanding
the world around us. But it's far more conjecture than we realise.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
For example, the actual area that the human eye can see clearly is
actually very small.  But as the eye scans a room, the brain builds up
a composit image that we think is much larger.  But in fact it is a
mental model that is made up of more of short term memories than what
it is really seeing at any given moment.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The brain is constantly doing this.  When you walk into a room you
have never been in before, your mind makes assumptions about that room
that are not supported by any direct evidence.  We assume, on past
experience that when we see a wall, there will be either another room,
or outside of the building there.  If you are in a submarine the brain
will assume that there is water on the otherside of a wall, or another
compartment. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This is far from being a perfect system, and the mental models that
the brain generate are often wrong.  The brain is driven to constantly
and relentlessly look for patterns that can be added into a mental
model.  And when there is insufficient information, the mental model
is influenced by what you &lt;i&gt;want&lt;/i&gt; to see.  If you are in a lifeboat
scanning the horizon or sky for rescue, a chance reflection, or shadow
will often be briefly percieved as a plane or boat.  People who have
very deeply held ideological and religious belief systems will often
take false possitive matches as evidence for building a mental model
that believes that they have actually seen things that in fact were
never there.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But this problem is not the sole domain of people who have seen Elvis
or Jesus in a grapefruit.  Humans have a very real limit on the amount
of change that they can incorporate into their mental model of the
world at any given moment.  If that change requires a person to set
aside set beliefs, the brain rebels and refuses to accept the evidence
before it.  People can only change so much in a lifetime after they
have reached a certain age.  And once you've hit that limit, you've
lost the ability to adapt.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As Alvin and Heidi Toffler have argued since their ground breaking
book Future Shock was published in 1970, the rate that things are
changing is increasingly exponentially.  But the human brain, which is
designed for life as hunter-gather species living on the African
Savannah, has to cope with a world that changes more in a year than
it's ancient ancestors would have to cope with in a lifetime.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It takes us time to internalize new ideas and concepts.  And if a new
idea is replaced with another idea before a person has had time to
internalize it, they will be left behind and stuck trying to use an
outmoded model of the world around them to understand a world that is
diverging further and further from their own internal mental model.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
William Gibson said that &quot;the future is here, it's just not evenly
distributed.&quot;  The Toffler's divide human development into three broad
stages, the first was was agricultural, the second was industrial, and
the third is based on information, and I would add, networking.  The
agricultural revolution is still alive and well in various remote
locations on the planet, and certainly the industrial revolution is in
progress in the developing world.  The post-industrial
information-networking revolution has really only taken hold in
highly developed areas of the planet in the last twenty years.  Within
each of these revolutions are many sub-stages of development.  The
agracultural revolution lasted milennia.  The industrial revolution
took place over hundreds of years.  But the same amount of change that
was spread over the industrial revolution has been compacted down into
less than a single lifetime, and we are still in the early stages of
the process.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
INSERT RANGANATHAN 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So what is the process that we first understand something that is new,
and then internalize it into our mental model?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Understanding all about context.  There can be communcation between
two parties unless they share a certain amount of information.  That
includes not only language, but cultural, economic and technological
assumptions about the world around them.  If you don't understand the
context that the person you are communicating with, there can be no
understanding and no communication will take place.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So when a person is confronted with something they don't understand
they first try to match what they see with something that they do
understand, even if they are very different things.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A common way of doing this is through the use of metaphors.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Technology has largely only found mass acceptance when a suitable
metaphor has been created that give people a cognitive foot hold they
can use to understand it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
People used a graphical display that had a &lt;i&gt;desktop&lt;/i&gt; where you could
arrange different things on your computer in the same way you would
arrange paper, books and tools on your desk.  If you wanted to throw
something away, you deleted it by moving it into a &lt;i&gt;trash can&lt;/i&gt;.
Windows were closer to pieces of paper or books that could be moved
around and placed on top of each other.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The Microsoft Office productivitiy suite of applications was a perfect
example of this.  A word processor, was an electronic type writer.  A
spreadsheet was a ledger book.  Outlook, used for email, was the
postal system, with an inbox and outbox, and letters that were
addressed to reciepients like memos in an office.  The presentation
software was foamcore on an easel &amp;#x2013; or slides projected from a slide
projector.  These were metaphors that the general public could
understand.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When the Internet came along, it didn't take off until the World Wide
Web made it possible to introduce a whole new set of metaphors.  A web
site was like a storefront, or book, or magazine or catalog or
newspaper.  Yahoo didn't start as a search engine, but an online
directory of web sites like the Yellow Pages.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Search never really had a proper metaphor linking it to the analog
world, but it wasn't able to really take off until people had
internalized the concepts behind software, operating systems and the
web before they could internalize it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The same happened with Social Media.  The metaphors behind social
media were the Bulletin Board, a part of a wall where one could pin
notes, ads and pictures for other people to see.  The other metaphor
was the mailing list &amp;#x2013; which you subscribed to and sent email to and
copies would then be sent to every one that had subscribed.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But there are only so many metaphors that people can successfully
internalize.  My father bought an early Macintosh that came with AOL.
He learned enough to be able to read and send email, and to use
instant messenger.  But that was about it.  As the Web and other
services became more popular, he just couldn't make the cognitive leap
that AOL was only a subset of the Internet.  My father is far from
being alone.  Many thousands of people have never made it beyond AOL.
It's almost as if AOL is Whoville, in Dr. Suess's &lt;i&gt;Horton Hears a
Who&lt;/i&gt;, but they believe that the tiny speck of dust they are living on
is a planet and that there is nothing beyond it&amp;#x2026;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The problem is that most people who have been left behind, never
understand that they are behind.  They have a fuzzy idea that their
mental model doesn't quite fit, but then they dismiss the idea
because, it works just fine for them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Anyone who has started a tech startup that working on the bleeding
edge will be all too familiar with this problem.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When pitching ideas for new startups, everything is new and the
founders fully understand that it will take some amount of effort to
get people to understand what they are building and why it's a good
idea.  But time and time again, it seems that most potential investors
simply are too far behind the technological curve for them to even
grasp technoligies that are in common use, let alone new technolgies
that will replace those.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Quite recently, I was thrown into a pitch without being told that I
was giving a pitch until it was already happening.  I explained that
we are building a distributed cloud service for SE Asia that will
adapt wildly successful cloud services worth hundreds of millions of
dollars for developing markets in the region.  But for some reason,
they couldn't get their head around the concept of a Cloud service,
because they couldn't make the distinction between an Telco and an
ISP.  We were conceptually lumped in with a Telco that he knew in
Phnom Penh which had spent millions of dollars and failed.  He had a
rough concept of a Telco, which used networks and computers to provide
communication services.  And since many Telcos offer Internet
connectivity, Internet services were just part of a Telco.  So the
idea of a Cloud Service was several generations of technology behind,
it was impossible for him to grasp the concept, and we were dismissed
out of hand.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In other cases, you might be able to explain a new technology in
relation to a metaphor that they do understand.  So you might make a
pitch around the Search metaphor.  Well, this company is a little like
Google Search in that is does A, B and C.  But it is &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; search
because it does D, E, F.  But you lost them as soon as you said it's
like Google because in their mind you're building a search engine.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This is always compounded by potential investors who sort of
understand what you are pitching, but then go to a trusted friend who
is a self proclaimed expert who has no idea what they are talking
about.  The result is inevitably the same.  &quot;Sorry, we can't become
involved&quot;, they say, &quot;it's already been done.&quot;  The fact that when
Google and Facebook had started, both search and social sites had
certainly &quot;already been done&quot; was irrelevant.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When &amp;#x2026;&amp;#x2026; was pitching Hotmail around Silicon Valley, he was nearly
laughed out of town.  People couldn't grasp the concept of &lt;i&gt;webmail&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This is very much a &lt;i&gt;failure of imagination&lt;/i&gt;, an inability not only to
understand what something is, but also a failure to see the potential
of something that they do understand in the future.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Even people who have been at the cutting edge of technological
development get it wrong sometimes.  Bill Gates refused to integrate
Microsoft products with the Internet until it was almost too late.
And Steve Ballmer waited so long to develop a proper mobile platform
that is probably is too late.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have a pretty good track record in recognizing technoligies that
will become big in the future.  But I've gotten it wrong too.  When we
were running our Hong Kong ISP, Huge Net in the mid-90's we had one
customer who gave away free Web Page hosting.  He kept adding new
customers, added servers and kept upgrading his bandwidth to handle
the traffic.  And yet he had no revenue stream.  He gave it all away
for free, and was loosing a lot of money every month in the process.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This went on for nearly three years, when suddenly he told us that he
had sold his company for $20 million.  We didn't have deep enough
pockets to have done this ourselves, but we'd completely missed the
emerging business model at the time to build up value in a company by
building up a large user base and then selling the company without
ever trying to generate revenue from the customer base.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Is there any way of reaching these people who are trapped in
hopelessly out of data metaphorical loops?  In most cases, the answer
is likely no.  Because the reason the future is distributed, is not
only not evenly distributed, it can never be evenly distributed as
each of us hits that wall and are left behind to spend the rest of our
lives trapped in techological conceptual tital pools.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr  /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Over very long periods of time, this context is all but lost, and the
meaning of things will drastically change.  Homer's Odyssey and Illiad
were not written, they were stories that evolved as part of the Oral
Tradition before writing systems had been invented in the Greek
States.  They were not so much an art form, as a means of preserving
the complexities of Greek culture and passing them on from one
generation to another.  The Muses were not inspirational, they
represented the collection of tools that the poet used to memorize and
perform these works and to pass them on to future generations
unchanged.  They acted as a kind of encyclopedia for a culture and
complex society.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But that original context surrounding Homer's works was nearly
forgotten as man moved from an Oral Tradition to a Written Tradition.
In the Written Traditional, narrative prose is a far better means of
recording and passing on information to other people today and to
future generations.  So poetry and Homer's encyclopedia gradually
became known only as a story, as entertainment and studied in a
context where poetry is a creative work of art.
&lt;/p&gt;





&lt;p&gt;
if you can see the relationship of
something you don't know, to something you do understand
&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;
Whether we realize it or not, people who had internalized a number of
different early stages of the info-network revolution have now hit
their ability to significantly change their mental models and are
being left behind.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>We Are Large We Contain Multitudes</title>
   <link href="http://chenla.la/2014/04/09/We-Contain_Multitudes.html"/>
   <updated>2014-04-09T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.paperplanes.de/2014/04/09/We-Contain_Multitudes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Do I contradict myself? Very well, then I contradict myself, I am
large, I contain multitudes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&amp;#x2013; Walt Whitman
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The full breadth of what we are working on is somewhat difficult to
grok at times.  This organizational chart shows all the different
pieces of how Chenla and our commerical sister company Repozit I/O fit
together should help.  Some of the items in the chart haven't been
publically released yet.  All will be revealed in good time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The chart is available as a &lt;a href=&quot;./files/chenla-org-chart-poster.pdf&quot;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt; and a somewhat large &lt;a href=&quot;./files/chenla-org-chart-poster-lg.png&quot;&gt;png&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/chenla-org-chart-poster-sm.png&quot; alt=&quot;chenla-org-chart-poster-sm.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What a Difference a Month Makes</title>
   <link href="http://chenla.la/2014/03/31/what-a-difference.html"/>
   <updated>2014-03-31T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.paperplanes.de/2014/03/31/what-a-difference</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Our Web server went down a month ago.  Sorry about that.  We're
now back up, using &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.io&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; to host the site.  Thanks Github!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Our new building is no longer the ghost (but not rat or coackroach)
infested, decrepit shell that it was when we signed the lease.  We've
made an enormous amount of progress in the last six weeks as these
photos will attest.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-front.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-front.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We have installed awnings on the side of the building as well as a
fixed metal awning on the first floor and a rollout vinyl awning on
the ground floor.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-awning.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-awning.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The first floor (American 2nd floor) is all but finished with the
walls and ceiling patched up, cleaned and painted, and the floors
sanded, the screws resunk, and stained and shellacked.  We have also
completely replaced the chaos of electricical wiring and the fuse box.
We can now handle the load from all of the computers that we will be
adding and nothing will short out.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-stairs.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-stairs.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We have also changed our original idea, and have swapped the office
and conference/podcasting studio.  Below is what will be the studio side.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-studio.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-studio.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And the side with the windows will become the office side.  We can
comfortably fit up to 12 desks into this space.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-office.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-office.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Heading downstairs, we have cut a new door that connects the
downstairs to the staircase leading upstairs.  Before, if you wanted
to go upstairs you had to go out the front and down and alley to get
to the entrance.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The toilet still needs some work, but looks much better already. The
tile floor was replaced, the plumbing fixed and a new sink installed.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-toilet.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-toilet.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Behind the toilet is the server room.  There isn't much to see, it's
just a plain white room with a tile floor.  We can fit up to four full
height racks in here.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-server.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-server.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The awful cabinates and several walls were knocked out for the
tutorial center, which will have enough round for five or six
workstations which can comfortably seat both a tutor and a student
together.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-tutorial.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-tutorial.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The last of the demolition was done here in the Naga Shop less than
four days ago.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-shop.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-shop.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There was a large window between the Naga Shop and the Cafe dining
area.  This has been removed and replaced with a wooden counter.  This
is Ruben working on the wood for the counter.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-cafe.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-cafe.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The door has been removed going into the kitchen, the squat toilet
turned into a pantry and a large window and pickup counter has
replaced a lot of the wall.  This is very much still a work in
progress.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-kitchen.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-kitchen.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There is still a lot of work left to be done, but we've come a long
long ways in the last six weeks.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Our New Building</title>
   <link href="http://chenla.la/2014/02/11/Our-New-Building.html"/>
   <updated>2014-02-11T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.paperplanes.de/2014/02/11/Our-New-Building</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
We are very pleased to announce that we have &lt;i&gt;finally&lt;/i&gt; managed to
lease a building here in Phnom Penh.  We had been promised a building
last year by persons who shall not be named.  But the national
elections and the uncertainty after the elections were contested put
many things on permanent hold.  So we made the decision to go ahead
and rent a building ourselves.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The new location is #155 E0/E1 on Street 110, in Daun Penh in Phnom
Penh.  The location is very good.  The building can be clearly seen
from Nordodom Blvd. and is only a street over from our present office
that is located in Brad's flat on Street 108.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-02-front.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-02-front.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As you can see from the next few shots, the ground floor will need a
bit of work.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The left side will be a cafe, with a large kitchen in the back &amp;#x2013; the
wall with the door will be largely knocked out and replaced with a
counter. 
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-02-cafe.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-02-cafe.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The right side will need the most work.  The half floor will be
knocked out entirely and turned into our &lt;i&gt;Naga General Supply&lt;/i&gt; shop.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-02-shop.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-02-shop.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Behind the shop, this forlorn looking area will be enlarged and become
the studyhall's tutorial and scanning center.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-02-tutorial.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-02-tutorial.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Don't worry, the toilet will be completely rebuilt.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-02-toilet.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-02-toilet.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Behind the tutorial room, not pictured, will be our server room which
will be large enough to hold four 19&quot; racks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There is also a very nice patio at the back of the building on the
first floor.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-02-back-patio.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-02-back-patio.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The first floor, which we will be using as office space is in far
better shape than the ground floor.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-02-office.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-02-office.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We got the keys about five days ago and are starting the long process
of rennovation.  The building will be the headquarters for Chenla and
our sister for-profit company, Repozit as well as the location for our
first Studyhall.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We'll be blogging our progress as things move along.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Douglas C. Engelbart (1925-2013) R.I.P.</title>
   <link href="http://chenla.la/2013/07/04/Douglas-Englebart-RIP.html"/>
   <updated>2013-07-04T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.paperplanes.de/2013/07/04/Douglas-Englebart-RIP</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Doug Engelbart died on Tuesday at the age 88 from kidney failure at
his home in Atherton, California.  Engelbart is best known as the
inventor of the mouse.  Let's just get it out of the way for those who
haven't seen it.  Here is the YouTube video of Engelbart's famous
&lt;i&gt;Mother of all Demos&lt;/i&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot;
src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/yJDv-zdhzMY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;
allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But Engelbart's vision and contribution went far beyond the mouse.
Dave Crocker  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ietf.org/mail-archive/web/ietf/current/msg80472.html&quot;&gt;said it best&lt;/a&gt; on the IETF mailing list:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Besides the considerable technical contributions of Doug's project at
SRI, theirs was a group that did much to create the open and
collaborative tone of the Internet that we've come to consider as
automatic and natural, but were unusual in those days.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Engelbart's real goal was to &lt;i&gt;augment human intelligence&lt;/i&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://worrydream.com/Engelbart/&quot;&gt;Bret
Victor&lt;/a&gt; has an excellent post that dispells many of the misconceptions
of Engelbart's work.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You can find an archive of all of his papers at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dougengelbart.org/&quot;&gt;Doug Engelbart
Institute&lt;/a&gt;.  There is a very good page at &lt;a href=&quot;http://cis471.blogspot.com/2013/07/doug-engelbart-passes-away.html&quot;&gt;CIS 471&lt;/a&gt; which has collected a
bunch of images and links that you might be interested in.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here's the obligatory link to his &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Douglas_C._Engelbart&quot;&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; article.  And obituaries
from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/07/04/technology/douglas-c-engelbart-inventor-of-the-computer-mouse-dies-at-88.html?ref=obituaries&amp;_r=1&amp;&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chicagotribune.com/entertainment/sns-rt-us-engelbart-obit-20130703,0,2472084.story&quot;&gt;Chicago Tribune&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/news/obituaries/la-me-douglas-engelbart-20130704,0,1651153.story&quot;&gt;LA Times&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/news/obituaries/la-me-douglas-engelbart-20130704,0,1651153.story&quot;&gt;Rueters&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2013/07/03/douglas_engelbart_mouse_creator/&quot;&gt;The Register&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Our very own &lt;a href=&quot;./bmf_overview.html&quot;&gt;BMF&lt;/a&gt; (Burr Metadata Framework) was largely inspired by
several of Englart's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dougengelbart.org/library/bibliography-summary.html&quot;&gt;papers&lt;/a&gt;.  They are well worth the time spent
reading them and we hope that his work will continue to be remembered
and inspire others for many years to come.  Thank you Doug Engelbart,
we all owe you an enormous debt of gratitude.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Studyhall Presentations</title>
   <link href="http://chenla.la/2013/07/02/Studyhall-Slide-Deck.html"/>
   <updated>2013-07-02T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.paperplanes.de/2013/07/02/Studyhall-Slide-Deck</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Just uploaded the &lt;a href=&quot;./slides/studyhall.html&quot;&gt;Studyhall Slide Deck&lt;/a&gt; on our &lt;a href=&quot;./slides.html&quot;&gt;Presentations&lt;/a&gt; page.
This will be the primary presentation that we will be using when
pitching the Studyhall.  This took a suprisingly large amount of work
to put together.  I hope the effort was worth it.  We expect the
Presentation will evolve over time, as we fine tune our pitch over
time, so expect it to change from time to time.  As always, feedback
is welcome.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The CD3WD Project</title>
   <link href="http://chenla.la/2013/06/30/CD3WD-Project.html"/>
   <updated>2013-06-30T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.paperplanes.de/2013/06/30/CD3WD-Project</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
I'm nearly finished reading Annalee Newitz's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Scatter-Adapt-Remember-Survive-Extinction/dp/0385535910/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1372597825&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=scatter,+adapt,+remember&quot;&gt;Scatter, Adapt, and
Remember&lt;/a&gt;.  I will have more to say about her book when I'm finished,
but I wanted to mention a the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cd3wd.com/&quot;&gt;CD3WD&lt;/a&gt; project which she wrote about in
the book.  Newitz described CD3WD as something that could potentially
be used as a primer to rebuild civilization after a collapse.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
CD3WD stated mission is a little more down to earth.  Their website
says that CD3WD's purpose is to create &quot;a free but high quality
collection of practical How-To Technical Development Information -
helping the 3rd world to help itself.&quot;  But Newitz is correct, in many
respects CD3WD could be used as a source for rebuilding after a
collapse.  The person behind CD3WD is Alex Weir, an expat
Microsoft-stack software programmer, based in Botswana.  He has
obviously been trying to sell the project to the NGO community:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The International Community and International and local NGO's for some
strange reason have zero or even negative interest in cd3wd - maybe
they can see the writing on the wall - a dynamic and self-sufficient
3rd world which has democratically and peacefully shaken off its
pro-Western and its anti-Western charlatan dictator-presidents will
have little or no need for NGO's. This lack of interest and hostility
is however regrettable, since their involvement could hasten their own
departure.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I think a case could also be made for encouraging the adoption and use
of OSS (Open Source Software) in developing countries, where vendor
lock-in is used as a means of keeping whole countries dependent on
multi-national corporations like Microsoft and Oracle.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Aside from that, Weir has put together an invaluable collection of
material and is making it available for free via the Web, Bit
Torrent, as well as on DVD and other physical media.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The danger is, that if he can't get NGO's and governments interested,
the project could be lumped in with the people who &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; most
interested in the collection at the moment; doomsday preppers,
survivalists and the &lt;i&gt;every man for himself&lt;/i&gt; crowd.  That would be be
a shame because the everything they stand is a &lt;i&gt;complete
opposite&lt;/i&gt; of what Weir is trying to achieve.  Weir wants to build a
better world, not give up hide in a bunker while everything falls
apart around them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I believe that part of the disinterest on the part of many NGO's is
that many people working for NGO's are from developed countries.  They
are middle-class latte slurpers, with iPhones and 3G access to the
Internet.  It's difficult to get them to understand &lt;i&gt;why&lt;/i&gt; such a
collection was needed, because you can swipe your finger across your
phone any time and &lt;i&gt;just Google it&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The second problem, from my perspective, is that the collection is
pretty much just a JBOF (just a bunch of files).  There is little
structure to the collection, and &lt;i&gt;no context&lt;/i&gt;.  A very large number
of the documents only make sense in the context for the audience they
were intended for.  There are all sorts of files that describe
methods for doing things like building with bamboo, but they are
worthless in SE Asia because they are written so that people from
Western countries can understand Asian building techniques.  They are
a terrible way of documenting those techniques for people who live
there.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And that contexual mismatch will only grow over time.  Weir has
undertaken a task of heroic proportions, but it is only a first step.
&lt;a href=&quot;./plancddr.html&quot;&gt;Plan CDDR&lt;/a&gt; is designed to take collections like this, and capture the
context that is needed to make the collection useful irrespective of
where it is used, and to remain useful for a very long time into the
future.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Making Sense of Things</title>
   <link href="http://chenla.la/2013/06/23/Making-Sense.html"/>
   <updated>2013-06-23T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.paperplanes.de/2013/06/23/Making-Sense</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
The days since my last post, I've been trying to make sense of where
to go next.  I'm terrible at the way most people blog.  This post is a
perfect example of what I don't like about blogs.  Lot's of pointless
little posts that provide bit-sized knee-jerk reactions to things for
the sole purpose of posting something.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
That defeats the purpose of the concept of the &lt;code&gt;Long Now&lt;/code&gt; by giving in
to the &lt;code&gt;Short Here&lt;/code&gt;.  And we don't want that.  But at the same time,
in a world of exponential change, out of sight for a couple of weeks,
isn't just out of mind, it's completely forgotten.  So we need to
strike some kind of balance between the two.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So instead of doing that, I'll start posting drafts of sections that
will become part of &lt;code&gt;Plan Cddr&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;StudyHall Template&lt;/code&gt;.  I'm not
that far away from having a complete outline of Plan Cddr, which we
will start publishing on &lt;a href=&quot;http://chenla.org&quot;&gt;http://chenla.org&lt;/a&gt;, which will be where we
will put all of the standards, designs, software and content that will
make up the body of work we've been talking about.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Once we have the outline in place, I won't have to worry so much about
jumping about, because each post can point to the context of where it
fits into the big picture in the outline.  Otherwise, I might post one
day about &lt;i&gt;cisterns in toilets&lt;/i&gt; and the next about the &lt;i&gt;future of the
nation state&lt;/i&gt; and there will be no idea of how all of it is part of a
coherent big picture.  Context is everything folks.  No context, no
meaning. 
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Plan Cddr: Backup, Primer & Restore</title>
   <link href="http://chenla.la/2013/06/19/Plan-Cddr-Overview.html"/>
   <updated>2013-06-19T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.paperplanes.de/2013/06/19/Plan-Cddr-Overview</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Just uploaded &lt;a href=&quot;./plancddr.html&quot;&gt;Plan Cddr: Backup, Primer &amp;amp; Restore&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;code&gt;Plan Cddr&lt;/code&gt; is
Chenla's Big Vision, that pulls together all the work we've done going
back to 1997.  The &lt;a href=&quot;./bmf_overview.html&quot;&gt;Burr Metadata Framework&lt;/a&gt;, was developed as the data
structure for the Backup.  The &lt;code&gt;Saltmine Server&lt;/code&gt; software that we are
developing will manage very long term archives and libraries encoded
in BMF.  And &lt;a href=&quot;./studyhall.html&quot;&gt;Studyhall Template&lt;/a&gt; provides a base unit for establishing
educational programs, research and development communities to build a
global, multi-lingual, distributed federated network of very long term
archives and libraries.  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We would love to hear a from you.  Since comments on the site are
still down, send email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:brad@chenla.la&quot;&gt;Brad&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ruben@chenla.la&quot;&gt;Ruben&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Website Comments & Tags</title>
   <link href="http://chenla.la/2013/06/18/Site_Comments_and_Tags.html"/>
   <updated>2013-06-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.paperplanes.de/2013/06/18/Site_Comments_and_Tags</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
I've spent a fruitless day trying to get Disqus Comments and Tag links
on the blog working.  No joy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So I've commented out both Comments and Tag links out until I can get this
sorted out&amp;#x2026;
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
