<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Chenla</title>
    <link>http://chenla.la</link>
    <language>en</language>
    <webMaster>brad@chenla.la (Brad Collins)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>2014-04-09T11:53:15+07:00</pubDate>
    <copyright>Copyright 2007-2010</copyright>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    <description>software development that flies</description>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are Large We Contain Multitudes</title>
      <link>http://chenla.la/2014/04/09/We-Contain_Multitudes.html</link>
      <pubDate>2014-04-09 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenla.la/archives/2014/04/09/We-Contain_Multitudes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Do I contradict myself? Very well, then I contradict myself, I am
large, I contain multitudes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&amp;#x2013; Walt Whitman
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The full breadth of what we are working on is somewhat difficult to
grok at times.  This organizational chart that shows all the different
pieces of how Chenla and our commerical sister company Repozit I/O fit
together should help.  Some of the items in the chart haven't been
publically released yet.  All will be revealed in good time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The chart is available as a &lt;a href=&quot;./files/chenla-org-chart-poster.pdf&quot;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt; and a somewhat large &lt;a href=&quot;./files/chenla-org-chart-poster-lg.png&quot;&gt;png&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/chenla-org-chart-poster-sm.png&quot; alt=&quot;chenla-org-chart-poster-sm.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      
      <category domain="http://chenla.la/tags/Studyhall Cambodia">Studyhall Cambodia</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a Difference a Month Makes</title>
      <link>http://chenla.la/2014/03/31/what-a-difference.html</link>
      <pubDate>2014-03-31 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenla.la/archives/2014/03/31/what-a-difference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Our Web server went down a month ago.  Sorry about that.  We're
now back up, using &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.io&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; to host the site.  Thanks Github!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Our new building is no longer the ghost (but not rat or coackroach)
infested, decrepit shell that it was when we signed the lease.  We've
made an enormous amount of progress in the last six weeks as these
photos will attest.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-front.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-front.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We have installed awnings on the side of the building as well as a
fixed metal awning on the first floor and a rollout vinyl awning on
the ground floor.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-awning.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-awning.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The first floor (American 2nd floor) is all but finished with the
walls and ceiling patched up, cleaned and painted, and the floors
sanded, the screws resunk, and stained and shellacked.  We have also
completely replaced the chaos of electricical wiring and the fuse box.
We can now handle the load from all of the computers that we will be
adding and nothing will short out.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-stairs.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-stairs.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We have also changed our original idea, and have swapped the office
and conference/podcasting studio.  Below is what will be the studio side.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-studio.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-studio.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And the side with the windows will become the office side.  We can
comfortably fit up to 12 desks into this space.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-office.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-office.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Heading downstairs, we have cut a new door that connects the
downstairs to the staircase leading upstairs.  Before, if you wanted
to go upstairs you had to go out the front and down and alley to get
to the entrance.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The toilet still needs some work, but looks much better already. The
tile floor was replaced, the plumbing fixed and a new sink installed.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-toilet.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-toilet.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Behind the toilet is the server room.  There isn't much to see, it's
just a plain white room with a tile floor.  We can fit up to four full
height racks in here.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-server.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-server.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The awful cabinates and several walls were knocked out for the
tutorial center, which will have enough round for five or six
workstations which can comfortably seat both a tutor and a student
together.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-tutorial.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-tutorial.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The last of the demolition was done here in the Naga Shop less than
four days ago.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-shop.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-shop.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There was a large window between the Naga Shop and the Cafe dining
area.  This has been removed and replaced with a wooden counter.  This
is Ruben working on the wood for the counter.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-cafe.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-cafe.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The door has been removed going into the kitchen, the squat toilet
turned into a pantry and a large window and pickup counter has
replaced a lot of the wall.  This is very much still a work in
progress.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-03-kitchen.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-03-kitchen.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There is still a lot of work left to be done, but we've come a long
long ways in the last six weeks.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <category domain="http://chenla.la/tags/Studyhall Cambodia">Studyhall Cambodia</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our New Building</title>
      <link>http://chenla.la/2014/02/11/Our-New-Building.html</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-11 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenla.la/archives/2014/02/11/Our-New-Building/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
We are very pleased to announce that we have &lt;i&gt;finally&lt;/i&gt; managed to
lease a building here in Phnom Penh.  We had been promised a building
last year by persons who shall not be named.  But the national
elections and the uncertainty after the elections were contested put
many things on permanent hold.  So we made the decision to go ahead
and rent a building ourselves.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The new location is #155 E0/E1 on Street 110, in Daun Penh in Phnom
Penh.  The location is very good.  The building can be clearly seen
from Nordodom Blvd. and is only a street over from our present office
that is located in Brad's flat on Street 108.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-02-front.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-02-front.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As you can see from the next few shots, the ground floor will need a
bit of work.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The left side will be a cafe, with a large kitchen in the back &amp;#x2013; the
wall with the door will be largely knocked out and replaced with a
counter. 
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-02-cafe.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-02-cafe.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The right side will need the most work.  The half floor will be
knocked out entirely and turned into our &lt;i&gt;Naga General Supply&lt;/i&gt; shop.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-02-shop.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-02-shop.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Behind the shop, this forlorn looking area will be enlarged and become
the studyhall's tutorial and scanning center.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-02-tutorial.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-02-tutorial.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Don't worry, the toilet will be completely rebuilt.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-02-toilet.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-02-toilet.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Behind the tutorial room, not pictured, will be our server room which
will be large enough to hold four 19&quot; racks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There is also a very nice patio at the back of the building on the
first floor.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-02-back-patio.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-02-back-patio.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The first floor, which we will be using as office space is in far
better shape than the ground floor.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/st110/st110-2014-02-office.png&quot; alt=&quot;st110-2014-02-office.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We got the keys about five days ago and are starting the long process
of rennovation.  The building will be the headquarters for Chenla and
our sister for-profit company, Repozit as well as the location for our
first Studyhall.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We'll be blogging our progress as things move along.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <category domain="http://chenla.la/tags/Studyhall Cambodia">Studyhall Cambodia</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Douglas C. Engelbart (1925-2013) R.I.P.</title>
      <link>http://chenla.la/2013/07/04/Douglas-Englebart-RIP.html</link>
      <pubDate>2013-07-04 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenla.la/archives/2013/07/04/Douglas-Englebart-RIP/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Doug Engelbart died on Tuesday at the age 88 from kidney failure at
his home in Atherton, California.  Engelbart is best known as the
inventor of the mouse.  Let's just get it out of the way for those who
haven't seen it.  Here is the YouTube video of Engelbart's famous
&lt;i&gt;Mother of all Demos&lt;/i&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot;
src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/yJDv-zdhzMY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;
allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But Engelbart's vision and contribution went far beyond the mouse.
Dave Crocker  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ietf.org/mail-archive/web/ietf/current/msg80472.html&quot;&gt;said it best&lt;/a&gt; on the IETF mailing list:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Besides the considerable technical contributions of Doug's project at
SRI, theirs was a group that did much to create the open and
collaborative tone of the Internet that we've come to consider as
automatic and natural, but were unusual in those days.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Engelbart's real goal was to &lt;i&gt;augment human intelligence&lt;/i&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://worrydream.com/Engelbart/&quot;&gt;Bret
Victor&lt;/a&gt; has an excellent post that dispells many of the misconceptions
of Engelbart's work.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You can find an archive of all of his papers at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dougengelbart.org/&quot;&gt;Doug Engelbart
Institute&lt;/a&gt;.  There is a very good page at &lt;a href=&quot;http://cis471.blogspot.com/2013/07/doug-engelbart-passes-away.html&quot;&gt;CIS 471&lt;/a&gt; which has collected a
bunch of images and links that you might be interested in.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here's the obligatory link to his &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Douglas_C._Engelbart&quot;&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; article.  And obituaries
from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/07/04/technology/douglas-c-engelbart-inventor-of-the-computer-mouse-dies-at-88.html?ref=obituaries&amp;_r=1&amp;&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chicagotribune.com/entertainment/sns-rt-us-engelbart-obit-20130703,0,2472084.story&quot;&gt;Chicago Tribune&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/news/obituaries/la-me-douglas-engelbart-20130704,0,1651153.story&quot;&gt;LA Times&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/news/obituaries/la-me-douglas-engelbart-20130704,0,1651153.story&quot;&gt;Rueters&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2013/07/03/douglas_engelbart_mouse_creator/&quot;&gt;The Register&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Our very own &lt;a href=&quot;./bmf_overview.html&quot;&gt;BMF&lt;/a&gt; (Burr Metadata Framework) was largely inspired by
several of Englart's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dougengelbart.org/library/bibliography-summary.html&quot;&gt;papers&lt;/a&gt;.  They are well worth the time spent
reading them and we hope that his work will continue to be remembered
and inspire others for many years to come.  Thank you Doug Engelbart,
we all owe you an enormous debt of gratitude.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <category domain="http://chenla.la/tags/BMF DougEngelbart">BMF DougEngelbart</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studyhall Presentations</title>
      <link>http://chenla.la/2013/07/02/Studyhall-Slide-Deck.html</link>
      <pubDate>2013-07-02 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenla.la/archives/2013/07/02/Studyhall-Slide-Deck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Just uploaded the &lt;a href=&quot;./slides/studyhall.html&quot;&gt;Studyhall Slide Deck&lt;/a&gt; on our &lt;a href=&quot;./slides.html&quot;&gt;Presentations&lt;/a&gt; page.
This will be the primary presentation that we will be using when
pitching the Studyhall.  This took a suprisingly large amount of work
to put together.  I hope the effort was worth it.  We expect the
Presentation will evolve over time, as we fine tune our pitch over
time, so expect it to change from time to time.  As always, feedback
is welcome.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <category domain="http://chenla.la/tags/studyhall">studyhall</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The CD3WD Project</title>
      <link>http://chenla.la/2013/06/30/CD3WD-Project.html</link>
      <pubDate>2013-06-30 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenla.la/archives/2013/06/30/CD3WD-Project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I'm nearly finished reading Annalee Newitz's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Scatter-Adapt-Remember-Survive-Extinction/dp/0385535910/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1372597825&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=scatter,+adapt,+remember&quot;&gt;Scatter, Adapt, and
Remember&lt;/a&gt;.  I will have more to say about her book when I'm finished,
but I wanted to mention a the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cd3wd.com/&quot;&gt;CD3WD&lt;/a&gt; project which she wrote about in
the book.  Newitz described CD3WD as something that could potentially
be used as a primer to rebuild civilization after a collapse.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
CD3WD stated mission is a little more down to earth.  Their website
says that CD3WD's purpose is to create &quot;a free but high quality
collection of practical How-To Technical Development Information -
helping the 3rd world to help itself.&quot;  But Newitz is correct, in many
respects CD3WD could be used as a source for rebuilding after a
collapse.  The person behind CD3WD is Alex Weir, an expat
Microsoft-stack software programmer, based in Botswana.  He has
obviously been trying to sell the project to the NGO community:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The International Community and International and local NGO's for some
strange reason have zero or even negative interest in cd3wd - maybe
they can see the writing on the wall - a dynamic and self-sufficient
3rd world which has democratically and peacefully shaken off its
pro-Western and its anti-Western charlatan dictator-presidents will
have little or no need for NGO's. This lack of interest and hostility
is however regrettable, since their involvement could hasten their own
departure.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I think a case could also be made for encouraging the adoption and use
of OSS (Open Source Software) in developing countries, where vendor
lock-in is used as a means of keeping whole countries dependent on
multi-national corporations like Microsoft and Oracle.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Aside from that, Weir has put together an invaluable collection of
material and is making it available for free via the Web, Bit
Torrent, as well as on DVD and other physical media.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The danger is, that if he can't get NGO's and governments interested,
the project could be lumped in with the people who &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; most
interested in the collection at the moment; doomsday preppers,
survivalists and the &lt;i&gt;every man for himself&lt;/i&gt; crowd.  That would be be
a shame because the everything they stand is a &lt;i&gt;complete
opposite&lt;/i&gt; of what Weir is trying to achieve.  Weir wants to build a
better world, not give up hide in a bunker while everything falls
apart around them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I believe that part of the disinterest on the part of many NGO's is
that many people working for NGO's are from developed countries.  They
are middle-class latte slurpers, with iPhones and 3G access to the
Internet.  It's difficult to get them to understand &lt;i&gt;why&lt;/i&gt; such a
collection was needed, because you can swipe your finger across your
phone any time and &lt;i&gt;just Google it&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The second problem, from my perspective, is that the collection is
pretty much just a JBOF (just a bunch of files).  There is little
structure to the collection, and &lt;i&gt;no context&lt;/i&gt;.  A very large number
of the documents only make sense in the context for the audience they
were intended for.  There are all sorts of files that describe
methods for doing things like building with bamboo, but they are
worthless in SE Asia because they are written so that people from
Western countries can understand Asian building techniques.  They are
a terrible way of documenting those techniques for people who live
there.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And that contexual mismatch will only grow over time.  Weir has
undertaken a task of heroic proportions, but it is only a first step.
&lt;a href=&quot;./plancddr.html&quot;&gt;Plan CDDR&lt;/a&gt; is designed to take collections like this, and capture the
context that is needed to make the collection useful irrespective of
where it is used, and to remain useful for a very long time into the
future.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <category domain="http://chenla.la/tags/plancddr archives developing-world">plancddr archives developing-world</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Sense of Things</title>
      <link>http://chenla.la/2013/06/23/Making-Sense.html</link>
      <pubDate>2013-06-23 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenla.la/archives/2013/06/23/Making-Sense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
The days since my last post, I've been trying to make sense of where
to go next.  I'm terrible at the way most people blog.  This post is a
perfect example of what I don't like about blogs.  Lot's of pointless
little posts that provide bit-sized knee-jerk reactions to things for
the sole purpose of posting something.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
That defeats the purpose of the concept of the &lt;code&gt;Long Now&lt;/code&gt; by giving in
to the &lt;code&gt;Short Here&lt;/code&gt;.  And we don't want that.  But at the same time,
in a world of exponential change, out of sight for a couple of weeks,
isn't just out of mind, it's completely forgotten.  So we need to
strike some kind of balance between the two.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So instead of doing that, I'll start posting drafts of sections that
will become part of &lt;code&gt;Plan Cddr&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;StudyHall Template&lt;/code&gt;.  I'm not
that far away from having a complete outline of Plan Cddr, which we
will start publishing on &lt;a href=&quot;http://chenla.org&quot;&gt;http://chenla.org&lt;/a&gt;, which will be where we
will put all of the standards, designs, software and content that will
make up the body of work we've been talking about.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Once we have the outline in place, I won't have to worry so much about
jumping about, because each post can point to the context of where it
fits into the big picture in the outline.  Otherwise, I might post one
day about &lt;i&gt;cisterns in toilets&lt;/i&gt; and the next about the &lt;i&gt;future of the
nation state&lt;/i&gt; and there will be no idea of how all of it is part of a
coherent big picture.  Context is everything folks.  No context, no
meaning. 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <category domain="http://chenla.la/tags/plancddr studyhall">plancddr studyhall</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plan Cddr: Backup, Primer & Restore</title>
      <link>http://chenla.la/2013/06/19/Plan-Cddr-Overview.html</link>
      <pubDate>2013-06-19 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenla.la/archives/2013/06/19/Plan-Cddr-Overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Just uploaded &lt;a href=&quot;./plancddr.html&quot;&gt;Plan Cddr: Backup, Primer &amp;amp; Restore&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;code&gt;Plan Cddr&lt;/code&gt; is
Chenla's Big Vision, that pulls together all the work we've done going
back to 1997.  The &lt;a href=&quot;./bmf_overview.html&quot;&gt;Burr Metadata Framework&lt;/a&gt;, was developed as the data
structure for the Backup.  The &lt;code&gt;Saltmine Server&lt;/code&gt; software that we are
developing will manage very long term archives and libraries encoded
in BMF.  And &lt;a href=&quot;./studyhall.html&quot;&gt;Studyhall Template&lt;/a&gt; provides a base unit for establishing
educational programs, research and development communities to build a
global, multi-lingual, distributed federated network of very long term
archives and libraries.  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We would love to hear a from you.  Since comments on the site are
still down, send email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:brad@chenla.la&quot;&gt;Brad&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ruben@chenla.la&quot;&gt;Ruben&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <category domain="http://chenla.la/tags/LongNow 10kClock 10KLibrary PlanCddr">LongNow 10kClock 10KLibrary PlanCddr</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Comments & Tags</title>
      <link>http://chenla.la/2013/06/18/Site_Comments_and_Tags.html</link>
      <pubDate>2013-06-18 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenla.la/archives/2013/06/18/Site_Comments_and_Tags/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I've spent a fruitless day trying to get Disqus Comments and Tag links
on the blog working.  No joy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So I've commented out both Comments and Tag links out until I can get this
sorted out&amp;#x2026;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <category domain="http://chenla.la/tags/website">website</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Studyhall Template</title>
      <link>http://chenla.la/2013/06/14/The_Studyhall_Template.html</link>
      <pubDate>2013-06-14 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenla.la/archives/2013/06/14/The_Studyhall_Template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
We have just updated the &lt;a href=&quot;http://chenla.la/studyhall.html&quot;&gt;Studyhall Template Project Page&lt;/a&gt;.  We have
been putting a lot of work into the studyhall template concept over
the last six months.  Our original goal was to establish the first
studyhall in Vientiane, Laos, which was only an hour's drive from
where I was living in Udon Thani, Thailand at the time.  We still
intend to eventually open a studyhall in Vientiane, but it won't be
our first.  Our plans abruptly changed when I was lured to Phnom Penh
with the enticement of a potentially lucrative unrelated project that
didn't pan out.  But in the process I found that I had permanently
relocated to Cambodia.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So our first studyhall will be built in Phnom Penh, near the Tonle &amp;amp;
Mekong rivers. We have been approaching government ministries, local
NGO's (and there are a &lt;b&gt;lot&lt;/b&gt; of NGO's in Cambodia) and local
universities to get their reaction and feedback to the idea.  The
response has been extremely positive.  So we are now putting together
a formal business plan and detailed budget and will be establishing
ourselves as what I call an un-NGO.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <category domain="http://chenla.la/tags/studyhall projects">studyhall projects</category>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
